VICENTE ORTIZ

(Web || JavaScript) Developer

vicente.ogc@gmail.com Github LinkedIn



I am a developer with over 8 years of experience, initially specializing in front-end development, which remains my passion. To expand my skill set and become more versatile, I have evolved into a full-stack developer, actively contributing to decision-making and solution-seeking throughout the entire development process. I pride myself on being autonomous, a proactive problem-solver, and a collaborative team player. Throughout my career, I've had the privilege of working alongside talented individuals, which has allowed me to grow both professionally and through personal side projects.

EXPERIENCE

Fullstack developer at Lansweeper

July 2019 - Nowadays

In this adventure I take part in the team in charge of creating an IT assets management SaaS solution. This software is developed with React on the front; node microservices on the backends; graphQL, gRPC and kafka for communication and kubernetes for infraestructure. All of this stick together with CI/CD on github and tests. In this position I find new challenges everyday like focusing on performance and scalability when coding, creating POCs quickly and working with distributed teams across the globe.

Fullstack developer at **Everis**

Juny 2016 - July 2019

I have worked on several projects, both for external clients and internal tools, in which I have used jQuery, Angular, Java, Spring, REST architectures, MySQL, MongoDB, git and Atlassian suite among others.

- I promoted in less than a year while working for a national insurance company.
- I was in constant communication with the client and adapting our solution to their needs.
- I managed several services and tools used across the whole company all around the world, I supported users, solved tickets and developed new features.
- I grew up as a mentor helping new colleagues and giving talks and workshops to the rest of the employees in the center about rising technologies.

VOLUNTEERING

Volunteering at **Everis**

July 2016 - July 2019

I have been an altruistic member of the organization in Alicante of several events such as <u>Women Tech Makers</u> or <u>Hash Code</u>, both planned by Google or <u>Space Apps Challenge</u> convoked by NASA. At the same time I work on side projects, personal and with other colleagues, exploring other technologies such as Amazon Web Services or Docker.

Qubic 2012 - 2017

Senior member of this student assosiaction dedicated to organize workshops and technical expositions, organize events in spanish univeersities and build engineering projects.

SKILLS

Technical

Javascript/Typescript/Node

React/Angular

HTML/CSS

REST/GraphQL

MongoDB/SQL

Soft

Agile methodologies

Teamwork

LANGUAGES

Spanish - Native

English - B2, Cambridge First (FCE)

EDUCATION

Electronics Engineering

University of Castilla La Mancha - 2015